Guide to the Planned Community Archives collection, 1960-2009
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 1: Reston, 1961-2006
  - Subseries 8: Scrapbook, 1961-1980
    - Universities Study Reston, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 27)
      497B.27 and 497D.22
    - Universities in Virginia Participate in Reston, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 28)
      497B.28 and 497D.23
    - Reston is a Magnet to Planners, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 29)
      497B.29 and 497D.24
    - The US Government Cites Reston, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 30)
      497B.30 and 497D.25
    - It Is Becoming Known at Home and Abroad, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 31)
      497B.31 and 497D.26
    - A Ford Foundation Grant For Reston's History, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 32)
      497B.32 and 497D.27
    - Private and Public Encouragement for Reston Schools, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 33)
      497B.33 and 497D.28
    - Reston Helps the County Cultural Effort, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 34)
      497B.34 and 497D.30
    - Fairfax Citizens Cooperate with Reston, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 35)
      497B.35 and 497D.29
    - Reston Announces Plan For Its Center For Government and Industry, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 36)
      497B.36 and 497D.31
    - First Construction Completed, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 37)
      497B.37 and 497D.34
    - Significant Dates, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 38)
      497B.38 and 497D.35
    - The Reston Community Fund is Established and Obtains Ruling Granting Tax Exempt Status, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 39)
      497B.39 and 497D.32
    - Deed of Dedication Reston, Section 1, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 40)
      497B.40 and 497D.33
    - Reston Master Plan, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 41)
      497B.41 and 497D.36
  - Subseries 9: General Information, 1965-2008
    The final subseries is general information from Reston. Included in the subseries is A Brief History of Reston, Reston Historic Trust, community theater programs, directories and other areas from Reston.
    - A Brief History of Reston, Virginia, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      480.39
    - A Place Called Reston, Reston Directory Special Edition, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      480.10
    - A Place Called Reston, Directory, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      480.29
    - A Pubic Notice, 1970s (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - AARP, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      477.9
    - An Historical perspective, 1970s (Box 33, Folder 6)
      480.51
    - Being Raised-Part I: Embry Cobb Rucker, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      14.3
    - Being Raised-Part I and II: Embry Cobb Rucker, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      14.4
    - BowDoin College, 1980s (Box 33, Folder 9)
      480.25
    - Calendar of Events, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      647.46
    - Cameron Glen Center, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Census Tables, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      477.8
    - Chronological Listing of Entertainers, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 13)
      247.28
    - Community Activities at Reston, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 14)
      480.46
    - Community Shelter, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 15)
      477.3
    - Cookbook, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Cookbook, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Deed of Resub, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Developer, 1990s (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Developer, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Directory (3 copies), 1968-1972 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Directory, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Directory, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Directory Useful Services Exchange (USE), 1993 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      480.14
    - E.B. White Talk on Pigeons, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      480.18
    - Facts, 1990s (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Facts, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Facts, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Facts, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Fact Sheets, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Fellows' Meeting, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 13)
      480.24
    - Georgetown-Reston Healthcare, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      500.1
    - Goals and Facts, 1990s (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Gordeco-Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      5.10
    - Gordeco Public Relations, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      3.9
    - Gordeco-Public Relations Slide Show, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      3.11
    - Gordeco Slide Show, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      3.12
    - Gordeco Slide Show, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      3.10
    - Gulf Oil Real Estate Development Company, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      4.8
    - Gulf Real Estate, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      4.5
    - Gulf Real Estate, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      4.6
    - Gulf Oil Real Estate Development Corporation, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      4.2
    - Harry Hilton: Presentation, 2000s (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Harry Hilton: Presentation, 2000s (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Harry Hilton: Presentation, 2000s (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Harry Hilton: Presentation, 2000s (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Harry Hilton: Presentation, 20001 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Historic Sites, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      12.14
      - Survey: National Parks Service, "Historic American Building Survey Inventory: A. Smith Bowman Bourbon Distillery", February 24, 1972; 1.
      - Survey: National Parks Service, "Historic American Building Survey Inventory: Brown's Chapel", July 13, 1970; 2.
      - Survey: National Parks Service, "Historic American Building Survey Inventory: Ox Hill Memorial Markers", November 16, 1970; 3.
    - Industrial Reston, 1970s (Box 36, Folder 7)
      461.15
    - Invitation for a Reception in HOnor of Saint Clair Cemin, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      647.42
    - Jane Wilhelm (Reston Forum), 2000s (Box 36, Folder 9)
      533.5
    - Lake Anne Nursery Kindergarten, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      477.7
    - Lake Anne and Lake Thoreau File, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      6.4
    - List of Photographs of Reston, 1970s (Box 36, Folder 12)
      13.6
    - Maps, 1990s (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Map of Reston, Virginia (Initial Development), 1960s (Box 36, Folder 14)
      1.30
    - Map of Reston, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Papers on Reston, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 16)
      500.2
    - Newsclippings, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Newsclippings, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Newsclippings, 1970s (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Newsclippings, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Open House Study, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Open House Study, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Open House Study, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Open House Study, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Petition, 1990s (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Photo Frame, 1990s (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Post Card, 1990s (Box 37, Folder 10)
      647.43
    - Post Card-Washington Plaza, 1970s (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Program-An Evening in Camelot, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      643
    - Program-"Applause", 1979 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Program-"Company", 1970s (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Program-"Guys and Dolls", 1979 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Program-"Gypsy a Musical", 1980 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Program-"How the Other Half Loves", 1980s (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Program-"Over Bounding Main", 1980s (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Program-"Painting Churches", 1988 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Program-"Private Lives", 1977 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Program-"The Fantasticks", 1976 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Program-"The Knack", 1976 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Program-"The Man Who Came To Dinner", 1981 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Program-"The Pajama Game", 1982 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Program-"Under Milk Wood", 1970s (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Program-"You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown", 1978 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Registration Forms, Programs: Reston, A Symposium, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      15.4
    - Reston: A Symposium, May 9 - 11, 1985; 1.
    - Reston-"A Brief History of Reston, Virginia" (Booklet), 1970 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      500.4
    - Reston: A Study in Beginnings (Volume I), 1965 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      481.1
    - Reston: A Study in Beginnings (Volume I, 1 of 3), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      481.2
    - Reston: A Study in Beginnings (Volume I, 2 of 3), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Reston: A Study in Beginnings (Volume I, 3 of 3), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Reston: A Study in Beginnings (Volume I, 1 of 3), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      481.3
    - Reston: A Study in Beginnings (Volume I, 2 of 3), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Reston: A Study in Beginnings (Volume I, 3 of 3), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Robert Simon's Notes on Missing Pages in "Reston: A Study in Beginnings", 1966 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      481.4
    - Reston Anniversary Committee, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      16.5
    - Reston Anniversary Committee, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      15.7
    - Reston Anniversary Committee, 1970s (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Reston Day by Day Calendar, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      480.11
    - Reston Documents, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Reston Handbook, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      480.13
    - Reston History, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 11)
      533.4
      - Illustration: Anonymous, "Lake Anne Air Conditioning System", October 15, 1964; 1.
      - Photograph: Anonymous, "Kroehler Traditional House - Dining Room", October 15, 1964; 2.
    - Reston History: Interviews, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      16.2
    - Reston History: Interviews, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      16.1
      - Interview: Nan Netherton, "Interview with Fran Steinbauer", January 28, 1982; 1.
      - Interview: Peter McCandless and Tom Grubisich, "Glenn Saunders, Jr.", December 14, 1984; 2.
    - Reston History: Interviews, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      16.3
    - Reston Historic Trust, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      533.3
      - Memo: James V. McGettrick to Martha V. Pennino, "Town of Wiehle", April 8, 1985; 1.
      - Report: Martha Pennino, "Island Walk Situation Report", March 4, 1985; 2.
    - Reston Historic Trust, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      533.1
      - Letter: Thomas W. Gittins to William B. Robertson, April 27, 1987; 1.
    - Reston Historic Trust, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      533.2
    - Reston Hospital Center, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      522.7
    - Reston Hospital Center, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      522.8
    - Reston Interfaith, Incorporated, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      19.12
      - Paper: Reston Interfaith Housing Corporation, "Affordable Housing for Low and Moderate Income Families in Reston", January 1984; 1.
    - Reston Resident's Handbook, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      480.12
    - Reston Second International Volksmarch, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      18.7
      - Reston's 2nd International Volksmarch, 1985; 1.
    - Reston Street Directory Map, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 5)
      1.33
    - Reston: T-Shirt and Invitation to Dedication of St. Thomas a Becket Catholic Church, Reston, 1980s (Box 41, Folder 6)
      14.6
    - Reston: The First 20 Years, Notes, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      16.4
    - Reston Town Center, 1990s (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Reston Town Center Rezoning, 1980s (Box 41, Folder 9)
      522.1
    - Report: Anonymous, "Appendix A: Town Center Development Land Area Summary", no date; 1.
    - Report: Anonymous, "Maximum Development Program", no date; 2.
    - Reston Town Center: Rezoning and Other Planning Materials, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 10)
      522.2
      - Application: Reston Land Corporation, "Reston Town Center Rezoning", November 1986; 1.
      - Letter: Joseph R. Stowers to Regional and Urban Design Committee of the American Institute of Architects, May 30, 1989; 2.
      - Press Release: Reston Land Corporation, "Reston Town Center Development Plans Unveiled", February 18, 1986; 3.
      - Report: Reston Land Corporation, "Reston Town Center Facts", no date; 4.
      - Report: Reston Land Corporation, "Reston Town Center Streetscape", no date; 5.
      - Report: Reston Land Corporation, "Reston Town Center: The Concept", no date; 6.
      - Letter: Cal Larson to J. Hunter Richardson, Jr., September 26, 1986; 7.
      - Illustration: Reston Land Corporation, "Reston Town Center Streetscape", no date; 8.
    - Reston Town Center: Rezoning Application, 1980s (Box 41, Folder 11)
      522.3
      - Application: Reston Land Corporation, "Reston Town Center Rezonings", February 3, 1987; 1.
    - Reston, Virginia-Two Maps, 1970s (Box 41, Folder 12)
      1.32
    - Reston, Virginia-Community Seniors, 1990s (Box 41, Folder 13)
      500.9
    - September: Reston International Center Opening Month Celebration, 1980s (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Shirley Olson, 1973-1976 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Shirley Olson, 1972 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Shirley Olson, 2008 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Survey for What Plays to Come, 1970s (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Symposium (20th Year Anniversary), 1985 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - The Chartered Institute of Secretaries, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      480.31
    - The Connection: A Question of Governance, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      544.8
    - The Reston Chorale, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Transportation, 1990s (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Transportation, 1990s (Box 42, Folder 10)
      522.4
    - Transportation, 1990s (Box 42, Folder 11)
      522.5
      - Table: Anonymous, "Reston Area Traffic Problems", March 1, 1988; 1.
    - Three Hundred Weeks of Sundays, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      14.5
    - Urban Land Institute Fall Meeting, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Warner Cable Franchise, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 14)
      522.6
    - Washington Plaza Reconstruction Rededication Ceremony, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 15)
      480.17
    - W.E.A. Programme of Classes, 1966-1967 (Box 42, Folder 16)
      480.30
    - Youth Activities-Reston Community, 2005 (Box 42, Folder 17)
      500.10
- Series 2: United States Planned Communities 1970-1996
  The material in this series relates to planned communities in the United States other than Reston, such as Columbia, Maryland, Evergreen Mills, Hawaii, Portland and others. The series is comprised of correspondence, plans, reports and other paperwork relating to the development of these communities.
  - Agreement and Certification, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    493.7
  - Agreement: Interstate General Development Incorporated, a Delaware Corporation, 1990s (Box 42, Folder 19)
    493.6
  - Ashburn Farm Architectural Guidelines, 1990s (Box 42, Folder 20)
    487.1
  - Ashburn Farm Association, 1990s (Box 43, Folder 1)
    487.2
  - Burke Centre-Newsclippings, 1990s (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Burke Centre-Reports, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Burke Centre-Correspondence, 1990s (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Chicago, 1990s (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Columbia Clippings, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    544.15
  - Columbia, Maryland-Discovery Park, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    547.2
  - Columbia, Maryland-Correspondence, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    547.3
  - Columbia, Maryland-Reports/Papers, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    547.5
  - Columbia, 1970s (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Columbia, Maryland-Newsclippings, 1980s-1990s (Box 43, Folder 11)
    546.2
  - Columbia Materials, 1970s (Box 44, Folder 1)
    543.4
  - Columbia Materials, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    543.3
  - Columbia Materials, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    543.2
  - Columbia Materials, 1972-1976 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    543.1
  - Columbia, Maryland, 1980s (Box 44, Folder 5)
    72.4
  - Columbia, Maryland, 1970s (Box 44, Folder 6)
    72.3
  - Columbia, Maryland, 1980s (Box 44, Folder 7)
    72.2
  - Columbia, Maryland, 1980s (Box 45, Folder 1)
    72.1
  - Developments of Regional Impact, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    491.1
  - Evergreen Mills-Affordable House, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Evergreen Mills-Comprehensive Plan, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Evergreen Mills-Consultants, 1989-1991 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Evergreen Mills-Consultants, 1989-1991 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Evergreen Mills-Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Evergreen Mills-General Information, 1989-1990 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Evergreen Mills-General Information, 1989-1993 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Evergreen Mills-General Information, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Evergreen Mills-General Information, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Evergreen Mills-Maps, 1993-1994 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Evergreen Mills-News Articles, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Evergreen Mills-Newsclippings, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Evergreen Mills-Newsclipping, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Evergreen Mills-Outparcels, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Evergreen Mills-Plans, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Evergreen Mills-Plans, 1991-1993 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Evergreen Mills-Policy, 1990-1992 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Evergreen Mills-Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Evergreen Mills-Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Evergreen Mills-Task Force, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Evergreen Mills-Tetra, 1995-1996 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Evergreen Mills-"Vision" Paper, 1988-1989 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Evergreen Mills-Vogel Acquisition, 1988-1989 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Evergreen Mills-Zoning Ordinance, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Evergreen Mills-Zoning Policies, 1988-1989 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Germantown, Maryland, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    73.5
  - Germantown, Maryland, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    73.6
  - Germantown Town Center, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    73.4
  - Greenbelt, Maryland-Development/Planning File, 1980s (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Greenbelt, Maryland, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    73.1
  - Greenbelt, Maryland, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    73.2
  - Greenbelt, Maryland, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    73.3
  - Hawaii, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    421.3
  - Hunter's Woods Citizens/Second Homeowners, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    500.3
  - Indemnity Agreement: Flower Mound, 1971 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    492.11
  - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust: The Woodlands Development Corporation to the Chase Manhattan Bank, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    493.4
  - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust: Ganaanda Development Corporation to the Chase Manhattan Bank, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    493.11
  - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust: Jonathan Development Corporation to First Trust Company of Saint Paul, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    493.10
  - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust: Maumelle Land Development Incorporated to the First National Bank in Little Rock Trustee, 1971 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    493.9
  - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust: Flower Mound, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    492.9
  - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust: Riverton, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    492.17
  - Limited Partnership Agreement: Flower Mound, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    492.10
  - Milton Keynes Plans, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    544.12
  - Montgomery Village News, 2002 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Montgomery Village Map, 2000s (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Montgomery Village: A New Town Twenty Years Later by William Neil Hurley, Jr., 1987 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - New Community Material: New Franconia, 1980s (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - New Community Material: Largo, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    543.5
  - New Community Material: Port Lincoln, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - New York State Urban Development Corporation Annual Report, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    488.16
  - Portland, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    421.8
  - Project Agreement Between the United States of America and Riverton Properties, Incorporated, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    492.16
  - Project Agreement Between the United States of America and The Woodlands Development Corporation, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    493.3
  - Project Agreement Between the United States of America and Maumelle Land Development, Incorporated, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    493.8
  - Puerto Rico Plan, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    488.13
  - Regional New Town Design, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    490.2
  - San Francisco, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    420.7
  - Security Agreement and Pledge: Flower Mound, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    492.12
  - Small-Scale Hydroelectric Power for Municipalities: The Case of Two New England Communities, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    489.10
  - 50,000,000 Dollars United States Government Guaranteed New Community Debentures of The Woodlands Development Corporation, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    493.1
  - 8,000,000 Dollars United States Government Guaranteed New Communities Act Debentures, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    493.5
  - 12,000,000 Dollars United States Government Guaranteed New Company Debentures of Riverton Properties, Incorporated, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    492.15
  - Underwriting Agreement, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    492.14
  - Village News, 1967-1970 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Washington Plaza, 1981 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Woodlands, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    488.14
  - Woodlands, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    493.2
  - Woodlands Development Plans, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 3)
- Series 3: International Planned Communities 1960-1990
  The material in this series relates to international planned communities in countries such as France, Great Britain, Israel, China and others. The materials are mostly promotional from the communities and other information regarding the development of the communities. Some of the material is in the foreign language while others are printed in English.
  - Administrative and Financial Problems of Creating New Towns in the Paris Area, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    491.20
  - Cadre de vie en Villes Nouvelles, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    491.13
  - Cairo, 1980s (Box 53, Folder 6)
    421.6
  - Crawley-Social Services, 1965-1966 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    480.36
  - Crawley Town Centre: The Commission for the New Towns, 1960s (Box 53, Folder 8)
    480.37
  - Crawley: Commission for the New Towns, 1960s (Box 53, Folder 9)
    480.35
  - Crawley New Town, 1960s (Box 53, Folder 10)
    480.32
  - England-New Towns of Britain, 1967-1973 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    545.2
  - England-New towns of Britain, 1967 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    545.3
  - England-New Towns of Britain, 1960s (Box 53, Folder 13)
    545.4
  - England-New Towns of Britain, 1960s (Box 54, Folder 1)
    546.1
  - Finland-Brochures, Postcards and Maps, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    13.10
  - Flexibility in New Town Development-United Kingdom (Athens Seminar), 1978 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    489.3
  - France-New Towns, 1977 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    491.15
  - French National Urban Policy and the Paris Region New Towns the Search for Community, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    544.9
  - French New Towns and Innovation, 1973 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    491.17
  - Hong Kong Rewards, 1970s (Box 54, Folder 7)
    422.3
  - Industrial Estate: The Commission for the NEw Towns, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    480.34
  - International New Town Association-Fifth Annual Conference, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    422.1
    - Paper: Baruch A. Kipnis, August 30 - September 7, 1981; 1.
    - Paper: F. Pechon, "Management of the New Towns: Budgeting and Financing Role of the Local Governments", August 30 - September 7, 1981; 2.
    - Paper: Jack A. Underhill, "Selected Review of the U.S. Management Experience Applicable to Planned Development in New and Renewing Communities", August 30 - September 7, 1981; 3.
    - Paper: Michael C. Ahn, "Demand Projections and Economic Modeling for New and Renewing Communities", August 30 - September 7, 1981; 4.
  - International Housing and Urban Development (HUD), 1973 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    495.4
  - International New Town's Association: Ministry of Development and State for Housing and Land Reclamation, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    421.4